<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to my Blog! on Portfolio Website for Bartek Mozdzen</title>
    <link>/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to my Blog! on Portfolio Website for Bartek Mozdzen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/blogs/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/climate/</guid>
      <description>Analysing temperature anomaliesCOVID-19 has put the environmental crisis on the back burne. The analysis of historical temperature anomalies below can serve as a reminder that the fight against climate change is still ahead of us!
We wanted to study climate change and used data on the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies. And we found the tabular data of temperature anomalies here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our world in data</title>
      <link>/blogs/gapminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/gapminder/</guid>
      <description>The following analysis focuses on key socioeconomic factors such as fertility rate, GDP per capita and life expectancy to observe a cross section of changes that our society has gone through across the globe.
Gapminder Dataset# load gapminder HIV datahiv &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;adults_with_hiv_percent_age_15_49.csv&amp;quot;))life_expectancy &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;life_expectancy_years.csv&amp;quot;))# get World bank data using wbstatsindicators &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;SP.DYN.TFRT.IN&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;SE.PRM.NENR&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;SH.DYN.MORT&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;NY.GDP.PCAP.KD&amp;quot;)library(wbstats)worldbank_data &amp;lt;- wb_data(country=&amp;quot;countries_only&amp;quot;, #countries only- no aggregates like Latin America, Europe, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TfL</title>
      <link>/blogs/tfl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/tfl/</guid>
      <description>COVID, the unprecedented lockdown and the sociological conundrum that followed have surely shaped our daily lives for the foreseeable future. These make even as trivial topics as bike rentals ripe for analysis. Below I will try to walk you through how I map the impact that COVID has had on the popular Santander bicyles available on every street corner in London.
First I import the latest data about daily cycle hires from TfL:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
